# JIANING LI



### A BRIEF BIO

I am currently a 5th year Ph.D candidate at Peking University. My research interests include computer vision and deep learning. My recent works focus on pose estimation, self/semi-supervised learning and person reidentification. Morever, I am interested in some related fields in computer vision, *e.g.*, multimedia retrieval, instance segmentation, detection and some related fields.

# **EDUCATION**

## Peking University (PKU), Beijing, China

2017 -- Present

Ph.D. candidate in Computer Applied Technology.

Advisor: Prof. Shiliang Zhang

### **Huazhong University of Science and Technology (HUST)**, Wuhan, China

2013 -- 2017

B.S. in School of Computer Science and Technology

# PUBLICATIONS

#### Journal:

- Pose-Guided Representation Learning for Person Re-Identification.
  Jianing Li, Shiliang Zhang, Qi Tian, Meng Wang, and Wen Gao.
  IEEE Trans. on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (PAMI, IF=17.9), 2019.
- Multi-Scale Temporal Cues Learning for Video Person Re-Identification.
  Jianing Li, Shiliang Zhang, and Tiejun Huang.
  IEEE Trans. on Image Processing (TIP, IF=9.3), 2020.

#### Conference:

- Joint Visual and Temporal Consistency for Unsupervised Domain Adaptive Person Re-Identification. **Jianing Li**, Shiliang Zhang. *ECCV*, 2020.
- Global-Local Temporal Representations For Video Person Re-Identification.
  Jianing Li, Shiliang Zhang, Jingdong Wang, Qi Tian, and Wen Gao. *ICCV*, 2019.
- Multi-scale 3D Convolution Network for Video Based Person Re-Identification. **Jianing Li**, Shiliang Zhang, and Tiejun Huang. *AAAI(oral)*, 2019.
- Pose-driven Deep Convolutional Model for Person Re-identification.
  Chi Su\*, Jianing Li\*, Shiliang Zhang, and et al..(\*equal contribution). ICCV, 2017.
- VP-ReID: Vehicle and Person Re-Identification System.
  Longhui Wei, Xiaobin Liu, Jianing Li, and Shiliang Zhang. ICMR, 2018

#### Under review:

- PolarPose: Single-stage Multi-person Pose Estimation in Polar Coordinates. **Jianing Li**, Shiliang Zhang. *IJCV*, 2021.
- Attribute-Disentangled Heatmap Prediction for Single-stage Multi-person Pose Estimation. **Jianing Li**, Shiliang Zhang. *CVPR*, 2022.

Google scholar citation: > 900.

### SERVICES

- Reviewer of ICCV, CVPR, ECCV, AAAI, VCIP, etc.
- Reviewer of PAMI, TIP, TMM, T-CSVT, TOMM, IET computer vision, etc.
- Invited tutorial, "Person Re-Identification: Recent Advances and Challenges", ICME 2021.
- Teaching assistant of Data Structure and Algorithms, Peking University.
- Teaching assistant of Multimedia Information Retrieval, Algorithms and Theories, Peking University.

# PROJECT EXPERIENCE

- Research on compact image features and hybrid index based massive image retrieval.. National Natural Science Foundation of China, 2016-2019.
- Large-scale Person Re-Identification. Cooperative projects with MSRA, 2018.
- Vehicle video content analysis and retrieval. Supported by Beijing's Natural Science Funds for Distinguished Young Scholar, 2018-2020.
- Content analysis and mining in ground air integration video for smart city. National Key R&D Program of China, 2020-2022.

# **PATENT**

- Deep learning based algorithm for image person re-identification.
  CN patent, No. 2017107801790
- Multi-scale 3D convolution network based algorithm for video based person re-identification.
  CN patent, No. 2019100130826
- Pose-guided representation learning method for image person re-identification.
  CN patent, No. 2019106779835
- Global-local temporal representation learning method for video person re-identification.
  CN patent, No. 2019114226010
- Joint visual and temporal consistency cluster method for unsupervised person re-identification.
  CN patent, No. 2020107071022

## SKILLS

- Programming Level: Familiar with Python, C/C++ and Cuda *etc.* programming language, and PyTorch and MXNET *etc.* deep learning framework.
- Research Field: My research interests include pose estimation, self-supervised/semi-supervised learning, instance segmentation, detection and some related fields.

### ♥ Honors and Awards

2021 Huawei Scholarship	May. 2021
2020 National Scholarship	Dec. 2020
2020 Peking University Academic Innovation Award	Oct. 2020
2020 Peking University Merit Student Pacesetter	Oct. 2020
2020 President Scholarship	Jun. 2020
2019 Baidu Scholarship Global Top 40	Oct. 2019
2019 Peking University Qingyun Shi Excellent Paper Award	Oct. 2019
2018 Peking University Academic Excellence Award	Oct. 2018
2017 2nd Prize in 4th China Graduate Contest on Smart City Technology and Creative Design	Aug. 2017